

### **Executive Summary**

After graduating with a BS in Applied Mathematics, I earned an MA in Mathematics Education and spent 9.5 years teaching mathematics in NYC public high schools. I am currently a Web Design student at the Startup Institute New York flexing my HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery muscles. I am looking to transition into a UX Design role at a startup with heart.

# Professional Experience

Leadership & Communication

Analysis

& Innovation

- Drove adoption of Common Core standards and industry best practices as a Department Chair, Professional Learning Team Facilitator, and Model Teacher
- Direct manager for 15 pre-service teachers, provided training in best practices for future leadership within public schools
- Developed and nurtured relationships with both external partners and internal stakeholders
- Represented Math for America as a speaker at national conferences
- Aggregated student achievement data to identify trends and adjust curriculum plans and pedagogical approach accordingly
- Assessed the needs of individual and groups of students through collection of qualitative and quantitative data
- Ran experiments to test the efficacy of pedagogical methodologies
- Served as a curriculum designer for EngageNY, McGraw Hill, and the School of One
- Created and executed activities which engaged users across diverse ranges of mathematical ability, motivation, and learning style
- Worked as part of a team to conceptualize and implement a residency model for pre-service teachers

### **Technical Fluency**

• • • • Google Drive Fluency

Advanced MS Word, Excel, and PowerPoint

- • HTMI
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Python
- •• C++
  - SQL

## **Employment History**

Jun 2009 – Sept 2015 High School Mathematics Educator Mathematics & Science Department Chair STEM Instructional Coach

The Urban Assembly School for Law and Justice Brooklyn, NY

Feb 2007 – Jun 2009 **High School Mathematics Educator**Manhattan Village Academy
New York, NY

## Selected Fellowships & Awards

Math for America Newton Fellow, New York, NY Math for America Master Teacher, New York, NY Verizon Design Lab Fellow, New York Hall of Science NSF Grantee to attend ICME-12, Seoul, South Korea

### Education

Startup Institute, New York, NY

Fall 2015

Web Design

Columbia University, Teachers College, New York, NY

February 2007

Master of Arts, Mathematics Education

Columbia University, Fu Foundation School of Engineering and Applied Science, New York, NY

May 2005

Bachelor of Science, Applied Mathematics minor in English City University of New York, Hunter College, New York, NY

June 2014 – December 2015

Continuing Education student in Computer Science

Relevant Coursework: CSCI127: Introduction to Computer Science, CSCI135: Software Design & Analysis, CSCI136: Supervised Programming Lab

### Interests

The great outdoors, SoulCycle, trendy diets, Chinese medicine, decaf coffee, educational equity, supporting women in STEM, Young Adult fiction, foreign travel, theater, Ken-Ken puzzles, and pretty much any show on Bravo.

### Links



https://www.linkedin.com/in/melanierosesmith



https://github.com/mrs2004